itchimes.com 2019-05-06

# IT Chimes Privacy Policy, This page Contains our Privacy Policy

**Last Updated:** 24th November, 2018

We here at IT Chimes, respect the importance of privacy of our clients. We understand that any user information provided by the user to us is for us to use them responsibly, and effectively for providing business value. Following the GDPR implementation, we have updated our Privacy Policy statement to reflect our Data usage policies and security measures we take to provide the best experience and service quality to our end users. This policy would apply to www.itchimes.com and all other websites on the internet that are owned and operated by IT Chimes &  Saffron Tech Pvt. Ltd. (hereafter referred as IT Chimes)

### Consent & Cookies

With the latest GDPR updates, we have actively revamped our data collection and authorization techniques. We highly value the importance of consent, and have implemented a mandatory “acceptance of privacy policy” on all our forms on the website. If you do not wish to share your details you may simply abstain from it by not accepting the terms.

If you want to verify your data is present or not in our database, you can request for the same at privacy@itchimes.com. This is only applicable if at some point of time you have engaged with IT Chimes, or any of our brands, and or accepted our privacy policies while submitting your details via forms/emails.

### Collection of Subscription Data

Other than data received through our website forms, we also have a feature of ‘Subscription’ on our website which we use to send out periodic newsletters and informations via emails to our users. This is not mandatory and an user can either uncheck the box during the form submission so as to not receive any company related information or news on their emails via periodic newsletters, or if subscribed already, can choose to unsubscribe at any time via the “unsubscribe” link present in the newsletters. User can also reach out us at [privacy@itchimes.com](mailto:privacy@saffronedge.com) incase they wish to unsubscribe from the newsletter subscription.

However, in any case in point, the user data we collect in order to send these newsletters fall directly under our user data privacy policy, where we do not misuse/sell/transfer the information to anyone outside of the company without express consent of the user themselves over a written agreement signed off by both parties.

### Collection and Usage of Personal Data

IT Chimes primarily collects 2 kinds of information. Personal and Behavioral.

**Personal Data:** This Data particularly deals with client and end user information that is shared with us voluntarily after signing/agreeing upon the privacy policy/Contracts. Personal Data usually contains information about:

  * **Name:**

  * **Email:**

  * **Primary/Secondary Contact Informations (Phone/IDs/Communication Channels):**

  * **Business Name(s)/URL(s):**

  * **Address:**

  * **Physical/Virtual Location(s):**

All of this data is securely preserved between the client and direct employees of IT Chimes. We take best measures to keep this data private and this is not revealed/disclosed/sold by us at any given point of time unless otherwise exclusively permitted/agreed upon by the client/user directly over written consent/agreement.

**Behavioral Data:** Due to the nature or Marketing industry we also receive and collect user data who are visiting/engaging/interacting on our websites. We also collect, study, analyze data of end customers/consumers/prospects and optimize various marketing campaigns for us and our client’s businesses, which is related to our projects. However, the information we collect here is more generic, vis-a-vis:

  * Age group
  * Gender
  * General Location (Not Addresses)
  * Tastes & Preferences
  * Names (only in cases of users filling out our contact forms/query forms on the website)

These information, however generic, are collected through tools such as Google Analytics, Ahrefs, SEMrush, Cookies, server logs etc. These informations are collected solely based on need of the campaign and making improvements to our interaction with users visiting our website. We also collect data on behalf our clients and have access to their users. This is contractually done and is part of our digital marketing services. This is again to provide better marketing interaction of the client with its users and running successful marketing campaigns.  Sometimes, Data is also provided by our clients from their inventory or research. We do not own these data and neither transact such data without formal approval/agreement with our client to do so.

Under no circumstance will IT Chimes be dealing with data, their exchange, or usage without prior approval/agreement from the client/users.

**Data Storage Policy**

  1. All data is stored on our secure servers and within our internal databases. Only IT Chimes officials, managers and active teams have access to information database. Incase of data breaches, all contacts are informed immediately within 72 hours of knowing.
  2. Once you have been contacted by a sales executive at IT Chimes your details will be stored to the database. If you expressly request to not be contacted or data be removed from our database, we will comply on formal requests (Email/Agreements).

You can access your information that we have on record at any time during our working hours. Please reach out to us at [privacy@itchimes.com](mailto:privacy@saffrontech.net)

## **Data Security & Infringement**

IT Chimes is committed to the security of customer information and we have security procedures in place to protect misuse or alteration of information under IT Chimes’s control.

IT Chimes may also enforce its [Terms and Conditions](https://www.itchimes.com/terms-and-conditions), including investigating potential violations of its Terms and Conditions to detect, prevent or mitigate fraud or security or technical issues; or to protect against imminent harm to the rights, property or safety of IT Chimes, its clients and/or the extended community.

## **Data Control**

At any point whilst IT Chimes is in possession of, or processing your personal data, you will hold the following controls:

  * **_Right of Access_** **–** you have the right to request a copy of the information that you have shared and we may have collected upon your express consent.
  * **_Right of Rectification_** **–** you have a right to correct data that we hold about you that is inaccurate or incomplete.
  * **_Right to Remove_** **–** in certain circumstances you can ask for the data we hold about you to be erased from our records.
  * **_Right of Migration_** – You have the right to migrate the data we hold regarding you or your business to another organisation. A formal consent will be required.

In case of further queries feel free to contact us at [privacy@itchimes.com](mailto:privacy@saffrontech.net)

Please note that we will not entertain the following requests:  
1) Information about other people;  
2) Opinions given in confidence;  
3) Repeat requests or privileged information.  
4) Other types of information may also be exempt under data protection laws (e.g. data relating to the commission of offences or estimates of damages).

**3rd Party Access to Private Data**

While we use 3rd party tools and softwares for our services to you, we are completely transparent about the resources in use and take prior consent before using them. For detailed information about these tool’s data collection policies, we encourage you to review them before consenting to usage. We are not liable or responsible for modifying or associating IT Chimes with these 3rd party tools at any point, unless otherwise stated.

### Exceptions of Data Usage

Other than the regular uses and policies guiding those usage and security of business data here are a few additional areas where we may use your data. Incase you do not wish to participate with these uses you can let us know at [privacy@itchimes.com](mailto:privacy@saffronedge.com).

  * Using your business/brand name in our case studies & portfolios. This doesn’t include actual inside information of your business or any information that can hurt your business in any way whatsoever.
  * Using your reviews/testimonials on our website(s), Google Business Profile, or Social Media (incase you exclusively reviewed us on our Social Media profiles)
  * Incase you have expressed interest and provided written consent in our company collaborating with a third-party vendor/agency/entity to work on a project.  

Incase of any of the above, you feel there is any breach, please reach out to us at privacy@itchimes.com

### **Policy Changes**

Any policy changes, either due to business reasons or future changes in legislation, will be updated on this page and notified on the website or through e-mail newsletters, as long as you are subscribed to them.

**Accepting the terms of our Privacy Policy**

By using the site you are accepting all the aforementioned  terms of our privacy policy statement. The terms are meant to be accepted or rejected as a whole and not in parts. If you have any questions, queries or concerns please contact us at[ privacy@itchimes.com ](mailto:privacy@saffrontech.net)

**Non-Liability in Online Communication**

Any mode of Online Communication has a wide range of variables due to which any one particular can not be held responsible for loss of data. Therefore, IT Chimes will not assume any responsibility for harm/loss of data you may experience in the process of sending/receiving information over the internet.
